<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Receiving on With Metta</title>
    <link>https://dhammacakka.github.io/withmetta/posts/receiving/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Receiving on With Metta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 18:29:27 +0630</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dhammacakka.github.io/withmetta/posts/receiving/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thumbs Up For Hitch-hiking</title>
      <link>https://dhammacakka.github.io/withmetta/posts/receiving/thumbsup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhammacakka.github.io/withmetta/posts/receiving/thumbsup/</guid>
      <description>Thumbs Up For Hitchhiking I remember when I was fourteen or so, some time in the mid eighties, when I started to test the realm beyond my parents’ advice. At that time, we had just moved to a new area in town and I decided to explore a bit with a visiting friend of mine. We walked to the town reservoir/park and then found a path back towards the general direction of my house which ended up putting us in the next town, but near the border.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ticket To Ride</title>
      <link>https://dhammacakka.github.io/withmetta/posts/receiving/ticket_to_ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhammacakka.github.io/withmetta/posts/receiving/ticket_to_ride/</guid>
      <description>Ticket to Ride I remember when I was in Colombo, Sri Lanka taking a bus in order to renew my visa at the immigration office.
In Sri Lanka, they have special coupons for monks to ride on the government “red buses” for free. However, the local buses in Colombo are rarely rarely government buses. A friend told me that if you walk on the first few steps before boarding and say that you do not use money, the conductor will usually let you on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“The Vote Was Nay”</title>
      <link>https://dhammacakka.github.io/withmetta/posts/receiving/vote_was_nay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhammacakka.github.io/withmetta/posts/receiving/vote_was_nay/</guid>
      <description>The Vote Was Nay By Randy, The Auto Worker For many years I have wanted to see Myanmar (Burma). I have never travelled outside of North America, and in my daily life, I am for the most part a homebody/recluse. In fact, fear has kept me from doing many things I would like to do in life. Going to Burma was almost another one of those many dreams I would not be able to live out because of this fear.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
