<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>With Metta</title>
    <link>https://withmetta.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on With Metta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 18:29:27 +0630</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://withmetta.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 12:01:35 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>A picture of me in Kilauea, HI, USA   About Originally, I wanted a place to post my Abhidhamma Articles, so I placed them in my Google Drive and made them public. However, as I updated the PDF, a new file link was created each time and I did not like that. I then asked a monastic senior friend if he would give me some space on his server so people could download my PDF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Different Kind of View</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/different_view/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/different_view/</guid>
      <description>A Different Kind of View Several years ago, I was working with a client (I am a psychotherapist). He was a man in his late 50’s who was working with me around a number of issues including dealing with painful and debilitating headaches of an unknown medical origin. He had spent many days in pain and visiting various doctors, getting scanned, prodded and poked to try to discover the source of his pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Small But Kind Act</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/smallkindact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/smallkindact/</guid>
      <description>Illustration from Victor Hugo et son temps (1881)   A Small But Kind Act, by Medini Richardson I volunteer as a Buddhist chaplain at a renowned children’s hospital , on my weekly visit to my regular ward I went to an isolation cubicle to chat to the mum who was holding a very small and sick 7 month baby. We chatted and got along really well. They were going to be in for a long time, several operations had already been performed on the dear baby, she was coping with this and another child of 6 years on her own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A wholesome snack</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/wholesome_snack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/wholesome_snack/</guid>
      <description>A wholesome snack It was an evening about 3 pm when we were on our way home. Me and my two sons. We have this small cafeteria close to our house and usually we stop by to pick up some snacks for tea in the evenings. My sons remained inside the rickshaw and I went inside the cafe. I saw this lady near the counter. I waited until she paid and I could see the staff behind the cashier whispering to each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dinner For One</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/dinner_for_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/dinner_for_one/</guid>
      <description>Dinner For One I remember when I was taking Pāli Language lessons at The American Burmese Buddhist Association in Brooklyn, New York some time in 1998. The monastery was virtually unknown to the local Americans at that time and I would go there on Fridays and leave on Sundays for my private lessons from the chief monk who spoke English. The monastery was in the heart of the city, and part of it was a warehouse… or better to say, it was a warehouse, and part of it was a monastery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lending A Hand</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/lending_a_hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/lending_a_hand/</guid>
      <description>Lending a Hand By Adam Glick This winter Boston set a record for snow and cold. We had nearly 5 feet of snow in 3 weeks and the temperatures were frequently below 0 degrees Fahrenheit. We live in the residential part of the city, so parking is typically a challenge. With that much snow everywhere, it was even more of a challenge. During one storm, on a Sunday night, my partner and I ventured out with our shovels to shovel out his car so that he could get out the next morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More than a bus driver</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/kauaibus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/kauaibus/</guid>
      <description>More Than A Bus Driver I overheard the bus driver telling this amazing story about his generosity to another passenger and afterwards, I asked him to tell me his story as an audio recording for this website. If you have a story, contact me through the submit a story page. This 6 minute story shows how kind a bus driver can be on his way home from work. He saw some stranded travelers who had a string of bad luck and reached out to give them a helping hand to literally get them off the ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Wish For Peace</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/some_wish_for_peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/some_wish_for_peace/</guid>
      <description>Some wish for peace, I did something (story below) I just got back from inviting 2 Muslims to serve at the head of the meal line for Tomorrow’s lunch at Pa-Auk. Everyone thought I was crazy and that the Muslims would kill me or at least shout at me as soon as I entered the compound. Instead they sat us down and offered us apples, and fruit juice with a happy and warm welcoming smiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thumbs Up For Hitch-hiking</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/receiving/thumbsup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/receiving/thumbsup/</guid>
      <description>Thumbs Up For Hitchhiking I remember when I was fourteen or so, some time in the mid eighties, when I started to test the realm beyond my parents’ advice. At that time, we had just moved to a new area in town and I decided to explore a bit with a visiting friend of mine. We walked to the town reservoir/park and then found a path back towards the general direction of my house which ended up putting us in the next town, but near the border.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ticket To Ride</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/receiving/ticket_to_ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/receiving/ticket_to_ride/</guid>
      <description>Ticket to Ride I remember when I was in Colombo, Sri Lanka taking a bus in order to renew my visa at the immigration office. In Sri Lanka, they have special coupons for monks to ride on the government “red buses” for free. However, the local buses in Colombo are rarely rarely government buses. A friend told me that if you walk on the first few steps before boarding and say that you do not use money, the conductor will usually let you on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wide and Shinging Eyes</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/wide_shining_eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/wide_shining_eyes/</guid>
      <description>Wide And Shining Eyes It was in 2011 when I came with my ex-wife to Myanmar. In Yangon, there are many begging children that sell postcards on the streets and near the tourist areas. Knowing this beforehand, I used to carry some sweets with me to give them instead of money. As you know, their parents send them to do this kind of work and they often earn pretty good money compared with the parents’ simple, hard labor on the field or in construction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“The Vote Was Nay”</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/receiving/vote_was_nay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:53:49 +0630</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/receiving/vote_was_nay/</guid>
      <description>The Vote Was Nay By Randy, The Auto Worker For many years I have wanted to see Myanmar (Burma). I have never travelled outside of North America, and in my daily life, I am for the most part a homebody/recluse. In fact, fear has kept me from doing many things I would like to do in life. Going to Burma was almost another one of those many dreams I would not be able to live out because of this fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sabbe satta</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/sabbe_satta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/posts/giving/sabbe_satta/</guid>
      <description>Sabbe Satta (metta) When a Buddhist monk says “sabbe satta,” that is a shorthand for metta practice. “Sabbe satta” means “all beings.” One of my friend’s collects the leftover food and cakes and says or acts on this everyday after each meal at our monastery. But in reality, even though he says “sabbe satta,” he really just seems to feed the birds with the leftover food and cakes. One day, I said to him, “So you are going to feed the birds?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://withmetta.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://withmetta.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>WithMetta.net  my server is gmail my user identifier is bksubhuti  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
